Dmitrii Maksimov

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER · DATA SCIENTIST

Erlangen, Germany

📕+49 15203762106 | 🗷 maksimov.dmitry.m@gmail.com | 🖸 Maksimov-Dmitry | 🛅 Maksimov-Dmitry | 🚨 maksimov.dmitry.m | 🕻 dmitrymaksimov

Summary

3+ years of diverse data science experience with specialties in market research, data visualization, market optimization and model deployment. **2+ years of diverse data/software engineering** experience with specialties in pipelines integration using Airflow, architecture design using AWS, database maintenance and deployment using docker.

In addition, while studying at the university and various courses(e.g. MADE from VK), I learned many skills like: **NLP, LLM, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Pytorch, Transformers, Huggingface, PyTorch Lightning, Optimization, Spark, Hadoop, Scala, Recommender Systems, kubernetes, mlflow, algorithms, A/B testing and data structures.**

Love to share knowledge with different communities. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for various tasks and learning new technologies and tools.

Skills_

MLOps AWS, Docker, GitHub, Retool, Linux, Bash, REST API, Google Cloud, CI/CD

Machine Learning, Statistical Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Probability Theory, ETL, Vertica, Search Engine Optimization,

PostgreSQL, Market Research, Parsing, Streamlit

Programming Python, SQL, SAS base, LaTeX **Languages** Russian, English, German

Work Experience _____

GFK Nuremberg, Germany

MLOPs & Work Study

Apr. 2023 - Present

- Migrated a Deep Learning model to Vertex AI on Google Cloud
- · Maintained the CI/CD pipeline
- Stack: Python, Google Cloud Platform, Vertex AI, Streamlit, CI/CD

T.C.R. International Cyprus

Data/Software Engineer Sep. 2021 - Present

- Developed and maintained processes for financial systems, with 90% of the processes developed with my active participation
- Optimized airflow dags which allowed reducing the cost of the astronomer by 70%
- Investigated strategies and solutions to reduce AWS infrastructure costs, optimizing resource allocation and usage
- Maintained the infrastructure, specifically working with AWS S3 and RDS
- Developed several AWS Lambda functions for automation and streamlined processing
- · Created a Deep Learning trading algorithm to optimize trading strategies and predict market movements
- Implemented processes for maintaining an extensive internal symbology database consisting of over 30,000 symbols
- · Stack: Python, AWS (S3, RDS, Lambda), Airflow, PostgreSQL, Retool, REST API, Docker

Nuremberg, Germany

Apr. 2022 - Apr. 2023

DATA SCIENTIST & WORK STUDY

Creating a tool to compare segmentations and their impact on the market

- Developing a method to detect AoI(areas of interests)
- Investigating cannibalisation effects
- Evaluating competitors algorithm
- Stack: Python, Google Cloud Platform, Streamlit, PostgreSQL

SDVOR Moscow, Russia

Apr. 2020 - Jan. 2022

• Creating an attribution model in advertising for SDVOR site using Markov chain as a result advertising costs decreased by 5%

- Programming ETL workflows for competitors site's parsing
- Building service to optimize price for sales using SAS, python, SQL, which increased the profit on some products by 10%
- Accomplishing computer vision model to compare planorgam and realogram via photo in a shop
- Creating telegram-bot as a server for different tasks
- Stack: Python, SAS, Vertica, PostgreSQL, Telegram API

Education

M.S. IN DATA SCIENCE Oct. 2021 - Present

BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Finished 1 semester

Moscow, Russia Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2021

BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

• GPA - 4.42, max - 5.0

Moscow, Russia

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

Extracurricular Activity

MADE at VK

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT

Sep. 2022 - Jun. 2023

- Gained expertise in different areas of ML (e.g. NLP, DL, Computer Vision, MLOps, basic ML, Python, ML in BigData, etc)
- Core member in a project to create a recommendation system for articles' authors
- · Core member in a project to create a User Request-Based Fake Web Document Text Generation system

ML at Mail.ru Group

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT

• Gained knowledge in basic ML

Moscow, Russia Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

Certificates

Jun. 2023 MADE Big Data Academy. Machine Learning Engineer, VK

405-67419

Oct. 2022 Completion of the Deep Learning Exercise, FAU

Mar. 2020 Labeled data learning, Coursera

Mar. 2020 Math and Python for data analysis, Coursera

2019 **C/C++**, Mail.ru Group

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL AWARDS

Jan. 2023 8th Place, Tensor Tournament

Erlangen, Germany Erlangen, Germany

Oct. 2022 **2nd Place**, Classification of Solar Cell Defects

DOMESTIC AWARDS

2021 **1st Place**, SDVOR Hacking Competition

Tyumen, Russia